<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.1 Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="venus" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
	ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.1">

	<title>VENUS</title>
	<conbody>
		<table>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="270*" />
				<colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="270*" />
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry colname="COLSPEC0" valign="top">
							<fig>
								<title>The Planet Venus</title>
							</fig>
						</entry>
						<entry colname="COLSPEC1" valign="top">
							<fig>
								<title>Surface Image of Venus</title>
							</fig>
						</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<row>
						<entry>
							<image align="middle" href="../images/venus1.gif" width="220"
								height="220" />
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<image align="top" href="../images/venus2.jpg" width="220"
								height="220" />
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>





		<p>Venus is the second planet from the Sun, and is Earth's closest
			neighbor in the solar system.
			Venus is the brightest object in the sky
			after the Sun and the Moon, and
			sometimes looks
			like a bright star in
			the morning or evening sky. The planet is a little
			smaller than
			Earth,
			and is similar to Earth inside. We can't see the surface of Venus
			from Earth,
			because it is covered with thick clouds. However, space
			missions to Venus
			have shown us
			that its surface is covered with
			craters, volcanoes, mountains, and big
			lava plains. The
			surface of
			Venus is not where you'd like to be, with temperatures that can
			melt
			lead,
			an atmosphere so thick it would crush you, and clouds of
			sulfuric acid
			that smell like
			rotten eggs to top it off!
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>What Has NASA Learned About Venus?</b>
			Craters smaller than 1.5 to 2 kilometers (0.9 to 1.2 miles) across do
			not exist on Venus, because small meteors burn up in the dense
			atmosphere before they can reach the surface. It is thought that
			Venus was completely resurfaced by volcanic activity 300 to 500
			million years ago. More than 1,000 volcanoes or volcanic centers
			larger than 20 kilometers (12 miles) in diameter dot the surface.
			Volcanic flows have produced long, sinuous channels extending for
			hundreds of kilometers. Venus has two large highland areas - Ishtar
			Terra, about the size of Australia, in the north polar region; and
			Aphrodite Terra, about the size of South America, straddling the
			equator and extending for almost 10,000 kilometers (6,000 miles).
			Maxwell Montes, the highest mountain on Venus and comparable to Mount
			Everest on Earth, is at the eastern edge of Ishtar Terra.
		</p>


    		<p><cite>http://solarsystem.nasa.gov/planets/profile.cfm</cite></p>
    
	</conbody>
	<related-links>
		<link format="html" href="http://solarsystem.nasa.gov/planets/profile.cfm"
			scope="external">
			<linktext>http://solarsystem.nasa.gov/planets/profile.cfm</linktext>
		</link>
	</related-links> 
</concept>
